Guide to the James M. McHugh papers,1930-1965.
McHugh, James M. papers,1930-1965.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James M. McHugh papers, 1930-1965.
2770
J. M.(James Marshall) McHugh 1899-
8.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, photographs, manuscripts, clippings, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are military correspondence and intelligence reports, personal correspondence, diaries, including a journal McHugh kept on his trip over the Burma Road (Dec. 1938-Jan. 1939), photographs (ca. 1300 items, many not precisely identified, of wartime figures, and colleagues and friends), manuscripts of articles and books, and printed items.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
James M. McHugh was born in Nevada, Missouri, graduated from the U.S. Naval Academy in 1922. Following training at Quantico he went to China in 1923 to study the country and its language. His father-in-law, Jacob Gould Schurman, who was president of Cornell University from 1892-1920, was then American minister to China.
McHugh spent over twenty years in China, where he served as intelligence officer for the 4th Marines and U.S. Asiatic Fleet, Shanghai, from 1933-1935, became special Assistant Naval Attache, American Embassy at Nanking, Hankow, and Chungking. He was Naval Attache and Naval Attache for Air from 1940-1943, serving as a special representative of Secretary of the Navy Frank Knox to Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek, with whom he was a close friend.
For his work in this capacity he was awarded the Legion of Merit. He was officer in charge of the Far East Secret Intelligence and served on the staff of the Fifth Amphibious Corps (G-5), was sent to Guam in 1944 to help plan the attack on Iwo Jima. An attack of malaria led to his recall in 1943; after which he was assigned to Navy Dept., to one of the forerunners of the present CIA.
After retirement in 1946, he was an economic consultant for corporations having interest in the Far East, including Jardine, Matheson & Co. (Hong Kong), and Balfour, Guthrie & Co. (New York).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are military correspondence and intelligence reports, personal correspondence, diaries, including a journal McHugh kept on his trip over the Burma Road (Dec. 1938-Jan. 1939), photographs (ca. 1300 items, many not precisely identified, of wartime figures, and colleagues and friends), manuscripts of articles and books, and printed items.
Subjects of the correspondence and reports to 1946 include China, the Sino-Japanese War, McHugh's association with the Chiangs, T.V. Soong, Ai-Ling Soong (Madame H.H. Kung), and other Chinese public figures, the management of the Bank of China, disputes among American interests with contracts for supplying the Chinese Air Force.
Other subjects include bribery of Chinese officials, administration of Lend-Lease in China, construction and use of the Burma Road, bombing of the British gunboat H.M.S. "Sandpiper," work of the American Volunteer Group (AVG), Japan and the Japanese people, bombing of Pearl Harbor, and activities of William Henry Donald, advisor to the Chiangs, Nelson Trusler Johnson, Clarence Gauss, Hyman G. Rickover, Evans F. Carlson, and Claire Lee Chennault.
After 1946, the letters are primarily analyses of events of national and international importance, such as the civil war in Indo-China and Vietnamese conflict, Soviet-American relations, Sino-Soviet relations, U.S.presidential elections, foreign policies of the Truman, Eisenhower, Kennedy, and Johnson administrations, written to and from various representatives of Jardine, Matheson & Co. and Balfour, Guthrie & Co., including Hugh David MacEwen Barton, David Bosanquet, Michael Alexander Robert Young-Herries, John Henry Keswick, William Johnson Keswick, and Erik Watts; also correspondence with Richard R. Smith, formerly with the British-American Tobacco Company (BAT) in Shanghai, on world affairs and on Smith's life in California.
Also, manuscripts and correspondence on an article by K.C. Wu (Kuo-chen Wu), former governor of Formosa; McHugh's wife, Maxine Davis, the writer; Major Ronald Aubry Boone, John H. Bruins, General Evans Fordyce Carlson, General Claire Lee Chennault, Madame Chiang Kai-shek (Mayling Soong), Oscar Sidney Cox, Commander John Marion Creighton, C.D. Culbertson, Lauchlin Currie, William Henry Donald, Herbert B. Elliston, Abijah Upson Fox, Clarence E. Gauss, Robin Gordon.
Other correspondents include Major Edward Gillette Hagan, Luther Hartwell Hodges, General Thomas Holcomb, Cordell Hull, Juang P'ing-heng (P.H. Whang), British Ambassador Archibald Clark Kerr, Claire (Lady) Keswick, Val St. J. Killery, Franklin William Knox, John Magruder, Rear Admiral Edward John Marquart, Lieutenant Commander Milton Edward Miles, Sir Geoffrey Alexander Stafford Northcote, Duncan Oppenheim, George M. Schurman, Charles Vincent Sheehan, Edgar Snow, Harold John Timperley, Rear Admiral Kemp Tolley, John Carter Vincent, and Admiral Harry Ervin Yarnell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McHugh, J. M.1899-; Barton, Hugh David MacEwen.; Boone, Ronald Aubry,; Bosanquet, David.; Bruins, John H.; Carlson, Evans Fordyce, 1896-1947.; Chennault, Claire Lee, 1893-1958.; Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1897-; Clark Kerr, Archibald.; Cox, Oscar Sidney.; Creighton, John Marion,; Culbertson, C.D.; Currie, Lauchlin Bernard.; Davis, Maxine.; Donald, William Henry, 1875-1946.; Eisenhower, Dwight D.(Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Elliston, Herbert B.; Fox, Abijah Upson.; Gauss, Clarence E.; Gordon, Robin.; Hagan, Edward Gillette,; Hodges, Luther Hartwell, 1936- .; Holcomb, Thomas,; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Johnson, Lyndon B.(Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Johnson, Nelson T.(Nelson Trusler), 1887-1954.; Juang, P'ing-heng.; Kennedy, John F.(John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Keswick, Claire,; Keswick, John Henry.; Keswick, William Johnson.; Killery, Val St. J.; Knox, Franklin William.; Magruder, John.; Marquart, Edward John,; Miles, Milton E., 1900-1961.; Northcote, Geoffry Alexander Stafford,; Oppenheim, Duncan.; Rickover, Hyman George.; Schurman, George M.; Sheehan, Charles Vincent.; Smith, Richard R.; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972.; Soong, Ai-ling, 1890-; Soong, T. V.(Tzu-wen), 1894-1971.; Timperley, Harold J.(Harold John), 1898-; Tolley, Kemp, 1908- .; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Vincent, John Carter, 1900- .; Watts, Erik.; Wu, Kuo Cheng, 1903-; Yarnell, Harry E.(Harry Ervin), 1875-1959.; Young-Herries, Michael Alexander Robert.; United States. Central Intelligence Agency.; United States. Embassy. China--Nanking.; United States. Navy.; United States. Office of Secret Service.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Personal Correspondence 1937-1946
    - 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Military Correspondence 1934, 1937-1946
    - 1934, Jan. 1937-Aug. 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sept. 1938-May 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - June-Dec. 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jan.-May 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - June-Dec. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jan.-June 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - July-Dec. 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1944, 1945, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, c. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Orders, Expense Sheets, etc., 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - William Henry Donald Biographical Data, 1938, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence 1947-1965
    - 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Jan.-April 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - May-Aug. 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Jan.-May 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - June-Aug. 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sept.-Dec.1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Jan.-March 1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - April-July 1954 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-April 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - May-Aug. 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jan.-April 1957 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - May-Sept.1957 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Jan.-May 1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - June-Aug. 1958 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-May 1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - June-Sept. 1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Jan.-March 1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - April-July 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Jan.-March 1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - April-June 1961 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - July-Dec. 1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Jan.-April 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - May-Aug. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Jan.-March 1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - April-July 1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-May 1964 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - June-July 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Jan.-Aug. 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Business Correspondence (cashier-Balfour, Guthrie & Co., Ltd.), 1947-1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Personal Business, 1954-1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1953, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Series II. Military Reports 1935-1942
  - Intelligence Summaries, Jan. 5-Feb. 12, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Intelligence Summaries, Feb. 19-March 19, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Intelligence Summaries, March 26-April 24, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Intelligence Summaries, May 1, 1935-June 9, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Attache and Intelligence Reports, 1938, Jan. 12-Nov. 2, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Intelligence Reports and Supplementary Notes, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Confidential Reports, Jan.-June 1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Confidential Reports, June 11-Dec. 1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Confidential Reports, April 13-July 14, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Confidential Reports, Aug. 1939-July 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Confidential Reports Notes re Reports, 1938, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Some duplicate copies re military matters (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Intelligence Reports, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Intelligence Reports, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Intelligence Reports, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Intelligence Reports, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Series III. Other Military Matters
  - Miscellaneous Memos, Orders, 1935-1945, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Public Vouchers for Purchases, c. 1937-1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Promotion and Cmmendation Correspondence, Orders,1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Allowance for Maintenance Sheets, 1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Orders, 1937-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Expense Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Claims for Reimbursement, c. 1942, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Military Awards, 1948-1949, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Special Subjects
  - Memoirs of Chiang Kai-shek by James M. McHugh (carbon) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chiang Kai-shek material China's Destiny (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - K.C. Wu material various rough drafts (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - K.C. Wu material miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - K.C. Wu material notes and rough draft (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chinese Air Force (Aircraft Manufacturers' Dispute), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - First American Volunteer Group: History and Status, Oct. 19, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chinese News Service Bulletins, 1947-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chinese Section: Letters written by McHugh (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chinese Section: General Correspondence, name and greeting cards (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chinese Section: Stamps, money, flag, etc. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chinese Section: Military passes and identification (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chinese Section: Road maps (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Certificate of Service to Yangtze River Rats, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Special Report to Congress, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Aid to China - Congressional Documents, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Series V. Draft for Book: The Unknown Era
  - Introduction (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Outline (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chapter I (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chapter II (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chapter III (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Chapter IV (W.H. Donald) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - [Materials following Chapter IV, begin.] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - [Materials following Chapter IV, cont.] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sun Yat-sen (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Chapter XIII: The Unification of China (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Chapter XIV: The Currency Crisis (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Chapter XV: Chinese Aviation and Chennault (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Sian Incident, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Carlson Incident, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Panay Incident, Dec. 1937 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - German Military Mission to China (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - U.S. State Department and Chinese Relations (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chiang Kai-shek and Stilwell (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum for the Publisher (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Final draft to Foreward, Chapter I, II, III, and ? (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Diary fragments, 1937 (Nov. and Dec.) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Diary fragments, 1938 (Jan.) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Diary fragments: The Burma Road Experience, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Diary fragments, 1939 (Mar.) (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Writings of McHugh and Maxine Davis
  - Elementary Mandarin Lessons: Notes (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Harvard University Seminar presentation, re: experiences in China during 1920's and 1930's for John Fairbank and John Carter Vincent, April 1959 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - China Must Help Herself; Article with 1st, 2nd, and finial drafts (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Chinese Economy; Article, notes, and materials for (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Maxine Davis; Dr. Curry Chops Wood (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Maxine Davis; They Did Not Run (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Maxine Davis; Mysterious Men on Mysterious Missions of State (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Introductory Mandarin Lessons (bound volume) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Maxine Davis; Miscellaneous notes (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Drafts, Carbons, and Miscellaneous for Book
  - Forward (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Chapter I (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Chapter II (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Chapter III (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - -- (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Early notes re Chiang Kai-shek (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Diary transcriptions and notes (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Biographical material (McHugh) and notes (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous resource material (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous resource material (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Series VIII. Other
  - Drafts for The Unknown Era (?) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Militarism in China by C. Martin Wilbur (carbon) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - The German Military Mission in China 1927-1938, an Instrument of the German Army in Gorsse Politik by Paul Wagner, 1963 (thesis) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - “The High Cost of Politics” by Philip L. Graham, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Legislation/Amendments/Acts, 1947-1959 (Box 14)
- Series IX. News clippings/Articles
  - “Why We Went to War in Korea” by Beverly Smith, the Saturday Evening Post, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Various clippings and articles, 1947-1965 (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
- Series X. Diaries
  - Diaries, notes, and addresses - 7 volumes, 1937, 1938, c.1945 (Box 15A, Folder 1)
  - Postal cards (early) - 3 envelopes including Saigon and Cambodia (Box 15A, Folder 2)
- Series XI. Photographs and Negatives
  - 1227 unidentified (Box 16)
    Numerous photographs taken in China roughly during the 1940-1942 period; many photos of bombing destruction, as well as air raid and execution victims; many unidentified Japanese military photos, troop movements, aviation airfield and Japanese occupation forces taken by Press Union Photo Service of Shanghai; Japanese military and civilian atrocity photographs taken by the China Information Committee photo service; many photos of McHugh and his friends; Ambassador Nelson T. Johnson, the Soong sisters (Ailing, Madame Kung; Mai-Ling, Madame Chiang and Chig-ling, Madame Sun Yat-sen), Chiang Kai-Shek, General Tsien, and other unidentified Chinese military men and other public figures
  - 127 unidentified (Box 17)
    More photos from the 1940-1942 period; many of bombing destruction, as well as air raid and execution victims; many photos of McHugh's ambassador trips and sightseeing documentation; photos of Jawaharlal Nehru; military photos documenting McHugh's award ceremony for receiving the Legion of Merit medal
  - Wooden chest of flash cards used in the teaching of Mandarin language (Box 18)
  - China policy, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - no title (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - General business / Far East (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Chinese currency crisis, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Chinese currency crisis, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bullitt (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - no title (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Articles - Indochina, Formosa, K.C. Wu (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Formosa - Rotary speech, Feb. 1955 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - China Act Bill - Testimony (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Chinese Airforce scandal, Washington Post (clippings discarded), Sept. 4-20, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Pros and Cons of Trade with Red China" rough drafts (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Formosa article, Sept. 26, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - "Pros and Cons of Trade with Red China" rough drafts (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - "Pros and Cons of Trade with Red China" rough drafts (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "Pros and Cons of Trade with Red China" (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - "Pros and Cons of Trade with Red China" (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Indochina material - rough draft (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Formosa - Notes and rough draft (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Saturday Evening Post - Memo on Marine Corps (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Hawaiian Pineapple Company - Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Hawaiian Pineapple Company - Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Hawaiian Pineapple Company - Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - BAT - local Washington correspondence (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - TPC - Repossession Documents (orig.) (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Universal Leaf Tobacco - General correspondence (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Universal Leaf Tobacco - General correspondence (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Universal Leaf Tobacco - General correspondence (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Richard H. Smith (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Richard H. Smith (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Tiencken (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - H.V. Tiencken (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - BAT correspondence - Louisville, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - BAT correspondence - Louisville (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - BAT correspondence - Louisville (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - L.G. Cousins (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - L.G. Cousins (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - BAT correspondence - London (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - BAT correspondence - London (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - W.F. Alexander (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - BAT correspondence, April 15, 1946-June 12, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Robert Harrison (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - R.J.E. Price (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Applications Japan Business Visits (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - (envelope) Diaries, 1949, 1953, 1954, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - (envelope) Diaries, n.a. (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - (envelope) Tape recording "Gittings" (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - (envelope) Tape recording "Capt. Christy" (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - (introductory information from 1993 microfilming) (Box 20)
- Series XII. Tobacco Trade
  - Misc TPC, memos/documents/correspondence, 1946-1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Tobacco Trade 1948
    - B.A.T. Balance Sheet, 1948-1950 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Rchard R. Smith (1), 1948 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Rchard R. Smith (1), 1948 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Copies of letters from Dick Smith re tobacco situation in China, March 1948 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Friendship cigarettes (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - H.V. Tiencken, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - D.M. Oppenheim, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - D.M. Oppenheim, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - R.J.C. Price, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - B.A.T. Richmond, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Harrison M. Robertson, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Harrison M. Robertson, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Richard R. Smith, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Richard R. Smith, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Richard R. Smith, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Universal Leaf - China (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Universal Leaf (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - W.F. Alexander, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - W.B. Christian, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - L.G. Cousins, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - U.S. Foreign Policy for a Postwar Recovery Program (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - U.S. Foreign Policy for a Postwar Recovery Program (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Tobacco Trade 1949
    - W.F. Alexander, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Richard R. Smith (1), Jan.-June 1949 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - L.G. Cousins, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - (Introductory information from the 1993 microfilming) (Box 20)
    - Richard R. Smith (1), Jan.-June 1949 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Robert Harrison, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Duncan M. Oppenheim, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Duncan M. Oppenheim, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Harrison M. Robertson, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - H.V. Tiencken, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Richard Smith (2), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Richard Smith (2), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Tobacco Trade 1950-1951
    - Extra copies of clippings, memos, and blind copies of letters (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Harrison M. Robertson (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - W.F. Alexander (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - BAT Correspondence - London, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - BAT Correspondence - London, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - F.W.H. Loudon (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Harrison M. Robertson (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Harrison M. Robertson (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Robert Harrison (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - L.G. Cousins (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - F.W.H. Loudon (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - F.W.H. Loudon (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - F.W.H. Loudon (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - F.W.H. Loudon (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - L.G. Cousins (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - BAT, May 1952 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Duncan M. Oppenheim (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Robertson/Yeaman, 1952-1954 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - F.W.H. Loudon, 1952-1964 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - F.W.H. Loudon, 1952-1964 (Box 20, Folder 53)
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous 1955-1959
  - Yeaman - Philippines (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Venezuela - Addison Yeaman (BAT) (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - G.F. Gelsthorp - Indonesia Newsletter (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Carribean Trip (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - no title (Box 20, Folder 58)
- Series XIV. Positive Microfilm Set
  - Personal Correspondence, 1937-1946 (Reel 1)
  - Personal Correspondence and Military Reports, 1935-1946 (Reel 2)
  - Military Reports, 1939-1965 (Reel 3)
  - Special Subjects, 1930-1965 (Reel 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1947-1954 (Reel 5)
  - Manuscripts, 1954-1957 (Reel 6)
  - Manuscripts, 1958-1960 (Reel 7)
  - Manuscripts, 1960-1962 (Reel 8)
  - Manuscripts, 1963-1965 (Reel 9)
  - Manuscripts - Unknown Era (Reel 10)
  - Manuscripts - Unknown Era XIII - XV (Reel 11)
  - Manuscripts - Miscellaneous Writings (Reel 12)
  - Congressional Documents, 1948-1949 (Reel 13)
  - Diaries - Post Cards, 1937-c. (1945) (Reel 14)
  - Photos, 1930-1965 (Reel 15)
  - Diaries, 1949, 1953, 1954, 1956, n.d.; Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Reel 16)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Reel 17)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Reel 18)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Reel 19)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1959; Newspaper Clippings, 1938-1965 (Reel 20)
  - Misc. items (negatives) (Reel 21)